Guide to the New-York Historical Society Museum Department Records 1765, 1830-2018 NYHS-RG 20
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Curatorial and Administration Files, 1934-2013; 167875; 39.92 Linear feet
  - Subseries III.C. Mary Black Files, 1940, 1968-1983; 168764; 6.25 Linear feet
    - Channel 13, 1977-1980; 169284 (Offsite-box 92, Folder 25)
    - Childs Gallery, 1978-1982; 169285 (Offsite-box 92, Folder 26)
    - Christmas Museum Proposal, 1978; 169286 (Offsite-box 92, Folder 27)
    - Cole, Lyman Emerson, 1971; 169287 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 1)
    - Cole, Thomas (artist), 1979-1981; 169288 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 2)
    - Complaint Letters re: Exhibitions, 1981; 169289 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 3)
    - Computers & Word Processing. Museum, 1982; 169290 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 4)
    - Conservation, N-YHS, 1981; 169291 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 5)
    - Cooper-Hewitt Museum of Design, 1976-1977; 169292 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 6)
    - Crafft, R.B. (artist), 1971; 169293 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 7)
    - Crawford, Joyce, 1981; 169294 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 8)
    - Crawford, Thomas (artist), 1981; 169295 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 9)
    - D. General, 1976-1980; 169296 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 10)
    - Damages, Insurance, 1970; 169297 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 11)
    - Decker, Malcolm, 1975; 169298 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 12)
    - Delanoy (artist), 1980-1981; 169299 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 13)
    - Denby, Mrs. William, 1976-1977; 169300 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 14)
    - DePeyster Limner, 1971; 169301 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 15)
    - Dexter Hall, 1968-1973; 169302 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 16)
    - Dover Publications, 1971-1977; 169303 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 17)
    - Draper, Ruth (accession sheets), 1977; 169304 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 18)
    - Dunn, Malcolm (appraiser), 1982; 169306 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 19)
    - Durand, Asher B. (artist), 1976-1980; 169309 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 20)
    - Durand, John (artist), 1980-1981; 169312 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 21)
    - Duyckincks (4 folders), 1973-1981; 169314 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 22-25)
    - E. General, 1979; 169316 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 26)
    - Eagles, 1970s; 169317 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 27)
    - Earle, Ralph (artist), 1977-1980; 169319 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 28)
    - Eastern Mass. Artist, 1982; 169321 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 29)
    - Edson, Almira, 1982; 169322 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 30)
    - Education, 1970-1973; 169323 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 31)
    - 1890 House, 1977; 169326 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 32)
    - English Folk Art, 1978; 169327 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 33)
    - Entrance Fees, 1980; 169328 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 34)
    - Erastus Salisbury Field Exhibition, 1981-1982; 169330 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 35)
    - European Painting, 1972; 169332 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 36)
    - Evaluations from Museum Workshop Program's Exhibition Workshop, 1978; 169335 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 37)
    - Exhibition Files (schedules, plans, proposals, etc.) (8 folders), 1973-1982; 169390 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 1-8)
    - F. General, 1973-1979; 169391 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 9)
    - Farancz, Alan (Paintings Restorer), 1970s; 169395 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 10)
    - Field, Erastus Salisbury, 1970-1978; 169397 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 11)
    - Film Project, Historic New York, Hudson River Film Co., 1980; 169398 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 12)
    - Fisher / Fitch, 1981; 169399 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 13)
    - Flint Institute of Arts, 1976; 169400 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 14)
    - Folk Art (3 folders), 1971-1982; 169401 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 15-17)
    - Foote, Mary (artist), 1973-1974; 169403 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 18)
    - Francis, Undated; 169408 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 19)
    - Freake Limner, Undated; 169410 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 20)
    - Freenan, George (artist), 1981; 169412 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 21)
    - Frost, J.O.J (artist), 1971; 169413 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 22)
    - Frymire, Jacob (artist), 1982; 169417 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 23)
    - G. General, 1972-1979; 169420 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 1)
    - Gallery Association of New York State, 1977-1980; 169422 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 2)
    - Gallery at the Old Post Office, 1982; 169423 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 3)
      Concerns Manhattan Observed and Breaking Ground exhibitions.
    - Gershinowitz, George, 1982; 169424 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 4)
    - Gifford, Sanford Robinson, 1981; 169425 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 5)
    - Gift/Donation Refusals, 1980-1981; 169426 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 6)
    - Gill, Jill (2 folders), 1975-1981; 169427 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 7-8)
    - Glass Files, 1976-1977; 169430 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 9)
    - Goelet List, Undated; 169433 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 10)
    - Gracie Mansion (3 folders), 1982; 169449 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 11-13)
      Includes Black's edited typescript for her "Gracie Mansion: A History of the Mayor's House" and related matter.
    - Greeley & Forest Forgeries. Research, Undated; 169460 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 14)
    - Greenleaf, Benjamin (artist), 1981; 169461 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 15)
    - Greitzer, Carol (councilwoman), 1981; 169464 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 16)
    - Guy, Francis, 1981; 169465 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 17)
    - H. General, 1971-1979; 169466 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 18)
    - Hartwell / Haspel (artists), Undated; 169467 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 19)
    - Heaton, John, 1972-1980; 169470 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 20)
    - Herot, George (artist), 1975; 169471 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 21)
    - Herring, James (artist), 1975; 169474 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 22)
    - Hicks, Edward, 1970-1980; 169476 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 23)
    - Hirschl & Adler Galleries, 1979-1982; 169480 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 24)
    - Hoelzer, Hiram (restorer), 1974; 169483 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 1)
    - Holsapple / Hopkins / Hovey, 1981; 169485 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 2)
    - Holt, Henry, 1978-1982; 169487 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 3)
    - Horton, Carolyn (restorer), 1978; 169488 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 4)
    - Hudson Valley Dutch Museum Survey, 1982; 169497 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 5)
    - Hudson Valley Studies, 1977; 169500 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 6)
    - Huntington, Daniel, 1970; 169501 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 7)
    - Hyde de Neuville, Baroness, 1972-1977; 169502 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 8)
    - I. General, 1976-1979; 169503 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 9)
    - Iconography, 1979; 169504 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 10)
    - Importance of Being Hyphenated, 1981; 169505 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 11)
    - Insley, Albert, 1982; 169506 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 12)
    - Interior Design Fair New York City, 1979; 169507 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 13)
    - Internal Revenue Service, 1981-1982; 169508 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 14)
    - International Celebration of Art, 1981; 169509 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 15)
    - International Center for Photography, 1978; 169510 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 16)
    - International Exhibitions Foundation, 1982; 169511 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 17)
    - Interoffice Memos, 1976-1977; 169512 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 18)
    - Inventories. N-YHS Manuscript Collection, Undated; 169513 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 19)
    - J. General, 1980-1981; 169514 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 20)
    - Jarvis, John Wesley, 1981; 169515 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 21)
    - John Judkin Memorial, 1978-1981; 169516 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 22)
    - Justus Dalee, 1974; 169517 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 23)
    - K. General, 1973-1978; 169518 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 24)
    - K and L. General, 1978-1979; 169519 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 25)
    - L. General, 1979-1983; 169520 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 26)
    - Kaplan Fund (2 folders), 1979-1982; 169521 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 27-28)
    - Kern, Arthur, 1979-1982; 169522 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 29)
    - Kilburn, Lawrence, 1981; 169523 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 30)
    - Kindig, Paul E. / Pennsylvania Butter Prints, 1982; 169524 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 31)
    - Kingston, NY, History of, 1974; 169525 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 32)
    - Knickerbocker Birthday, 1979; 169526 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 33)
    - Landscape Catalog, 1971-1982; 169529 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 34-35)
    - Lesueur, 1974; 169531 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 36)
    - Lewis, Jerry (Federal Hall Chairs), 1982; 169532 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 37)
    - Lighting Fixtures. Case, 3rd Floor West Corridor, Undated; 169536 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 38)
    - Limners of the Upper Hudson, 1968-1978; 169538 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 39)
    - Love Galleries, 1982; 169577 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 1)
    - Lynes, Russell, 1981; 169578 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 2)
    - Lyons, Louis and Paul Hollister (Glass), 1977; 169579 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 3)
    - M. General, 1978-1979; 169580 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 4)
    - Maentel, Jacob (2 folders), 1971-1980; 169581 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 5-6)
    - Magriel, Paul, 1980; 169582 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 7)
    - Manhattan Now (Manhattan Observed), 1981; 169583 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 8)
    - Marling, Jacob, 1977; 169584 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 9)
    - Minnigerode, Marietta (artist), 1980; 169604 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 10)
    - Movers (Global), 1977; 169605 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 11)
    - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1981; 169606 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 12)
    - MTA Bus Ex. / Dover Book, 1982; 169607 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 13)
    - MTA. N-YHS Station, 1979; 169608 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 14)
    - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1978-1982; 169609 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 15)
    - Museum of American Folk Art, 1971-1972; 169612 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 16)
    - Museum of the City of New York, 1979; 169613 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 17)
    - N. General, 1976-1980; 169610 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 18)
    - National Gallery of Art, 1979-1982; 169611 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 19)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1982; 169614 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 20)
    - Nehemiah Partridge Exhibition, 1982; 169615 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 21)
    - New York City Buildings Records Collection, Planning Committee, 1979; 169616 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 22)
    - New York City Heath & Hospitals Exhibition, 1981; 169617 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 23)
    - New York Gallery of the Fine Arts (document photoreproductions), Undated; 169618 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 24)
    - N-YHS. Membership, 1981; 169619 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 25)
    - N-YHS. Museum (7 folders), 1970s-1982; 169620 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 26-32)
      Includes files on budgets (1980s), lighting, facilities, Museum Committee (1980), and other matters.
    - N-YHS. Publications (2 folders), 1973-1980; 169621 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 33-34)
    - New York in Aerial Views, 1980-1981; 169622 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 1)
    - New York Nostalgia, 1973; 169623 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 2)
    - New York State Education Dept., 1981; 169624 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 3)
    - New York Street Furniture, 1982?; 169625 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 4)
    - Newtown Bee, 1977-1982; 169626 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 5)
    - 19th Century American Paintings Exhibition, 1981; 169627 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 6)
    - Of the Land's Bounty, Undated; 169628 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 7)
    - Other Historical Societies, 1970-1976; 169629 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 8)
    - P. General, 1978-1982; 169630 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 9)
    - Pace College, 1976-1981; 169631 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 10)
    - Painter's Materials, 1970; 169632 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 11)
    - Paintings. Artist Identified, 1970-1976; 169633 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 12)
    - Paperweights. Book (Hollister) and Exhibition (2 folders), 1971-1977; 169634 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 13-14)
    - Partridge, Nehemiah, 1971-1980; 169635 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 15)
    - Patroon / Paul, 1979; 169636 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 16)
    - Paul Stewart, 1979; 169637 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 17)
    - Pavesi, Rudy, 1980-1981; 169638 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 18)
    - The Peales, 1971-1979; 169639 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 19)
    - Peck, Sheldon, 1976-1981; 169640 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 20)
    - Peckham, Robert, 1979-1981; 169641 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 21)
    - Penniman, John Ritto, 1981; 169642 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 22)
    - Pennington, Samuel, 1982; 169643 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 23)
    - Phillips, Ammi (2 folders), 1972-1982; 169644 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 24-25)
    - Photographer. David Anderson, 1981; 169645 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 1)
    - Photographer. Bill Aron, 1978-1980; 169646 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 2)
    - Pierrepont Limner / Pollard Limner, 1977-1981; 169647 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 3)
    - Pinney, Eunice, 1971; 169648 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 4)
    - Pintard Fellows, 1970-1973; 169649 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 5)
    - Pintard Genealogy, Undated; 169650 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 6)
    - Pintard Prospects, 1970-1972; 169651 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 7)
    - Pitigliani, Letizia, 1976-1979; 169652 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 8)
    - Piwonka, Ruth, 1982; 169653 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 9)
    - Portrait Catalog, 1970s; 169654 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 10)
    - Portraits. Artist Unknown (2 folders), 1970-1977; 169655 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 11-12)
    - Powers, Asahel, 1980; 169656 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 13)
    - Prevost, Victor, 1975; 169657 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 14)
    - Prentis Rooms, 1979; 169658 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 15)
    - Prior, William Mathew, 1973-1981; 169659 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 16)
    - Public Relations / Carole Sorell Inc, 1980-1981; 169660 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 17)
    - Publicity, 1970-1974; 169661 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 18)
    - Publishing Center for Cultural Resources, 1976-1981; 169662 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 19)
    - R. General, 1976-1980; 169663 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 20)
    - Radovanovitch, Georges, Undated; 169664 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 21)
    - Rapalje / Reiss, 1980; 169665 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 22)
    - Redecoration of N-YHS, 1972-1973; 169666 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 23)
    - Reproduction Program, 1976; 169667 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 24)
    - Reynolda House, 1978; 169668 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 25)
    - Rice Mansion, 1979; 169669 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 26)
    - Rifkind, Carole, 1979; 169670 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 27)
    - Riordan, Marguerite, 1982; 169671 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 28)
    - River, Bowery, Mill & Beaver, 1973-1976; 169672 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 29)
    - Rockefeller, Rodman (IBEC), 1979-1982; 169673 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 30)
    - Rogers, John, 1970-1981; 169674 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 31)
    - Rosenthal, Odeda, 1980-1982; 169675 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 1)
    - Ross (Arthur) Foundation, 1981-1982; 169676 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 2)
    - Ruder & Finn Fine Arts, 1981; 169677 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 3)
    - S. General, 1976-1982; 169678 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 4)
    - Salmagundi Club, 1970s; 169679 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 5)
    - San Francisco Fine Arts Museum, 1981; 169680 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 6)
    - Sandak Interest, Undated; 169681 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 7)
    - Sandburg, Carl, 1978; 169682 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 8)
    - Savage, A.J., 1982; 169683 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 9)
    - Sawitsky, 1981; 169684 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 10)
    - Scrimshaw, 1976; 169685 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 11)
    - Sculpture, 1980; 169686 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 12)
    - Seaman (artist), 1972; 169687 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 13)
    - Seminars, 1970-1976; 169688 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 14)
    - Senate House State Historical Society, 1981; 169689 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 15)
    - Sessions, Ralph D., 1981; 169690 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 16)
    - Sharples / Sheffield, 1978-1982; 169691 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 17)
    - Shelburne Museum, 1981; 169692 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 18)
    - Ship at South Street, 1982; 169693 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 19)
    - Shute (artist), 1977; 169694 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 20)
    - Sinclair Glass, 1975; 169695 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 21)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restoration, 1981; 169696 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 22)
    - Smibert / Smillie / Steward, 1981; 169697 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 23)
    - Society for the Preservation of Long Island Antiquities, 1981; 169698 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 24)
    - Society of Illustrators, 1981; 169699 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 25)
    - Society's Sculpture, Undated; 169700 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 26)
    - South Street Seaport Museum, 1971-1980; 169701 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 27)
    - Speedwell Village, 1978; 169702 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 28)
    - St. Marks Church in the Bowery (Oral History), 1981; 169703 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 29)
    - Staff Meetings, 1970s; 169704 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 30)
    - Stained Glass, 1981; 169705 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 31)
    - Staten Island Historical Society, 1980; 169706 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 32)
    - Stewart, Mrs. William Rhinelander, 1976; 169707 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 33)
    - Stock, Joseph (3 folders), 1974-1979; 169708 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 1-3)
    - Stoneware Jugs in 3rd Floor Corridor, Undated; 169709 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 4)
    - Storage, 1981; 169710 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 5)
    - Strawberry Festival, 1978; 169711 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 6)
    - Sturbridge Limner, 1977; 169712 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 7)
    - Suppliers to Museums, Undated; 169713 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 8)
    - Sweetwater Editions, Undated; 169714 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 9)
    - Synagogue Survey, New York City, 1980; 169715 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 10)
    - T. General, 1982; 169716 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 11)
    - Ten Eyck / Thompson, 1977; 169717 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 12)
    - Terra Museum of American Art, 1981-1982; 169718 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 13)
    - Textiles, 1971-1982; 169719 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 14)
    - Tiffany Conservation Project, 1980; 169720 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 15)
    - Toys, 1973; 169721 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 16)
    - George Brown Toy Sketchbook, 1971; 169722 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 17)
    - Trenton High Falls, 1972; 169723 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 18)
    - Tri-Delta Charity Antiques Show, 1979; 169724 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 19)
    - Trumbull, John, 1940, 1975-1981; 169725 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 20)
      Includes 1940s correspondence between the United States Trust Company of New York and the Museum of the City of New York concerning the bequest of a Trumbull portrait to MCNY, subsequently renounced in favor of N-YHS.
    - Tuthill, Abraham / Tuttle, 1977-1981; 169726 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 21)
    - Twentieth Century Painting, 1975; 169727 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 22)
    - Ukrainian Museum, 1977; 169728 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 23)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1980; 169729 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 24)
    - V and W. General, 1977-1981; 169730 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 25)
    - Van Dyck / Van Name, 1981; 169731 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 26)
    - Van Rensselaer Limner, 1974-1975; 169732 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 27)
    - Vanderlyn, John, 1971-1974; 169733 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 28)
    - Vanderlyn, Pieter, 1980-1981; 169734 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 29)
    - Vanderlyn, Peter. Research, 1971-1976; 169735 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 1)
    - Vandervere, 1979; 169736 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 2)
    - Velvet Limner, 1981; 169737 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1979-1982; 169738 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 4)
    - Vose Galleries of Boston, 1978-1982; 169739 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 5)
    - Wall / Ware, 1980; 169740 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 6)
    - Washington, George. Portraits, 1979; 169741 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 7)
    - Waterfront / Stephanie Hollyman Tugboats, 1980; 169742 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 8)
    - Watherston, Margaret (conservator), 1972-1982; 169743 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 9)
    - Watson, John. Article (3 folders), circa 1979; 169744 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 10-12)
    - West Point, 1981; 169745 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 13)
    - Wetherbee, Isaac / Wiggin, 1981; 169746 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 14)
    - Whitney Museum / "Three Centuries of American F. Painters", 1978; 169747 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 15)
    - Williams, Micah & William, 1971-1974; 169748 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 16)
    - Wigmore Fine Arts, 1981; 169749 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 17)
    - Willson, Mary Ann (artist), Undated; 169750 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 18)
    - Wiltshire / Young / Wilks, 1981; 169751 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 19)
    - Winiker, Barry M., 1981-1983; 169752 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 20)
    - Wollaston, John, 1976; 169753 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence (4 folders), 1970-1972; 169754 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 22-25)
    - Correspondence (11 folders), 1973-1977; 169755 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 1-11)
    - Correspondence (10 folders), 1977-1981; 169756 (Offsite-box 104, Folder 1-10)
    - Correspondence (8 folders), 1981-1982; 169757 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 1-8)
  - Subseries III.D. Holly Hotchner Files, 1970-1994; 169760; 14.83 Linear feet
    The subseries is arranged by general subject categories. The categories were defined by the processing archivist in order to simplify and summarize the presentation of the many individual folders in the subseries. The archivist developed the categories based on observation of the relationship of groups of folders within the original storage boxes. Although the archivist did make some adjustments to their arrangement, in large part the folders found together remain that way.
    N-YHS restricts Board of Trustee and Executive Office files for 35 years following the departure of a President and Chief Executive Officer. This subseries includes some files related to Board and Board Committee matters, and those files are restricted accordingly. Specifically, the files date primarily from the administration of Barbara Knowles Debs and the interim leaders that followed her (1988-1994) and so they are restricted until 2030. While the restriction applies, those files may be used only by, or with the permission of, the President and Chief Executive Officer, the head of the Museum Department, or their designee.
    Biographical/Historical Note
    Holly Hotchner joined N-YHS in 1984 to play a leadership role in the conservation initiatives of the Museum Department. The mid-1980s to early 1990s were a turbulent time in N-YHS's history and Hotchner's scope of responsibility gradually expanded, formally and informally, over this period. By 1989, with the departure of museum curator Ella Foshay (1984-1989), Hotchner was promoted from Chief Conservator to Museum Director. At the same time, the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architecture (the Print Room) was transferred from the Library to the Museum, where it would remain organizationally until 1998. The Security Department was also transferred to Hotchner's leadership at this time. As Museum Director and a member of the senior management team in the late 1980s and early 1990s, Hotchner was closely involved with N-YHS's facilities and fiscal planning, the effort to broaden the museum's professional staff, and the initiative to refine the institution's collections policy and the associated deaccessioning process. By mid-1993, at the height of N-YHS's fiscal crisis and as a result of large numbers of staff lay-offs, resignations, and other departures, only Hotchner remained as the senior level executive at N-YHS. Her role narrowed in early 1994 as N-YHS Co-Chair "Pug" Winokur took over responsibility for the Museum while Hotchner focused on the deaccessioning initiative of the time and the planning of certain major exhibitions. Later In 1994 Hotchner also left N-YHS.
    Separated Materials Note